webfloss.com 2011-05-21

# Privacy Policy — High Class Living on a Middle Class Budget

_Welcome! To get the latest deals from Webfloss.com you can subscribe to the[Daily Email Digest](http://feedburner.google.com/fb/a/mailverify?uri=HighClassLivingOnAMiddleClassBudget), fan me on [Facebook](http://networkedblogs.com/blog/webfloss), or Follow on Twitter [@webfloss](http://twitter.com/webfloss). Thanks for visiting!_

**Privacy Policy**

WebFloss is committed to protecting your privacy. That is why we have adopted this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is intended to describe how information is processed and used.

Note: Webfloss.com is NOT responsible for the privacy policies for any sites we link to and highly encourage you to read the privacy policy for ANY site you visit PERIOD. 

Please note that by visiting and using WebFloss.com you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

What Information is WebFloss gathering about its visitors and how is it being used?

Every computer connected to the Internet is provided with a domain name (e.g. earthlink.net) and an IP Address (e.g. 192.164.13.145). When a visitor requests a page from within the Web Floss website, our Web Servers automatically identify and log the HTTP request that is made to our Web Server. This information reveals nothing personal about you. In fact, the only information that we automatically gather and log is as follows:

> • The IP Address of the Site that may have Referred you.  
>  • Your IP Address  
>  • The Web Page that you may have linked to us from, if any.  
>  • The Product Identifier for Version and Make of Browser (e.g. Firefox 3.0)  
>  • Search Words or Terms that are passed from a Search Engine (e.g. Google, Yahoo, or MSN) 

There is absolutely nothing special about the information just described, and the practice of collecting this data has been generally standardized by virtually every Web Server on the Internet today.

The purpose for this information is actually two-fold. One, Web Floss has found it advantageous to examine visitor traffic in its aggregate, so that we can ensure maximum compatibility for the various Browsers and Operating Systems that visit our site. Additionally, as any business should attest, it is our desire to generate greater amounts of visitor traffic. By analyzing visitation patterns, referring URLs and Search Engine terms, we can strategically enhance our exposure on the Internet.

What about Cookies?

Cookies are also subject to a number of misconceptions, mostly based on the erroneous notion that they are computer programs that run on the browsing computer. In fact, cookies are simple pieces of data that affect the operation of a web server, not the client, and do so in very specific ways. In particular, they are neither spyware nor viruses. Webfloss.com ad revenue is tracked at ad load and when the ad is clicked. The function of these cookies is solely for the purpose of paying commissions when a consumer creates a lead or makes a purchase. 

You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of your browser. Typically, by accessing the browser’s help feature you can obtain information on how to prevent your browser from accepting all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being sent. Choosing to block cookies from our website will only effect the ability to make a purchase directly from WebFloss.

What other information does WebFloss request?

We will never request personal information for the purposes of conducting a survey or to have someone contact you for additional information. We only request an email address if you would like us to reply to a sent message or if you’d like to subscribe to our email digest. We maintain a strict “No Spam” policy that means we do not intend to sell, rent, or otherwise give your e-mail address to a third-party. EVER.

In addition, WebFloss will not send you e-mail that you have not agreed to receive. If you are a member of our Daily Digest List, you will be contacted once per day at around 11pm EST with a summary of all posts for the day. You have the option of “Unsubscribing” from our Mailing List at any time, thereby disabling any further such e-mail communication from being sent to you.

If you comment with a QUESTION on Webfloss in a post or article and include your email address, we will reply via the email address entered. If you comment with a QUESTION on Webfloss in a post or article and do not leave an email address we will reply on the actual post or page the comment was left. We will NEVER use/store your email address for any further communications and/or ANY other reason but to reply to your initial question. 

Will Web Floss disclose the information collected to Third Parties?

WebFloss will ONLY disclose our log file information when required by a verified law enforcement agency.

WebFloss uses strict precautions to keep the information disclosed to us secure. WebFloss also provides “links” to a wide variety of other web sites on the Internet. We are not responsible for their Privacy Policies or how those web sites manage information about their users. We strongly urge you to check with those web sites to determine their privacy policy.

Webfloss.com reserves the right to change the Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page so that you are always aware of the information that we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

Added October 2009:

_We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp_
